Finding aid for Peter Sparling papers, 1961-2013 0312 Aa2
Bentley Historical Library
Peter Sparling papers
1961-2013
1970-2000
Bentley Historical Library
Sparling, Peter.
0312 Aa2
6 linear feet
89.5 GB online
Peter Sparling is Professor of Dance at the University of Michigan School of Music. Well known as both performer and choreographer, he has danced with Martha Graham and Jose Limon. Papers consist of materials relating to Sparling's dance training, performance, and teaching including background materials; choreography notes and sketches; correspondence; clippings and publicity from dance companies with whom he was associated; programs and reviews; photographs, video and film of performances; and posters.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were donated by Peter Sparling (donor no. 8992) beginning in 2001.
Accruals
Periodic additions to the records expected.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open to research.
Access to some of the online digital files in the Performance, Audition, and Rehearsal Videos series is restricted to viewing the Bentley Library Reading Room and at the University of Michigan School of Music, Theatre and Dance. Equipment needed to view the DVC-Pro digital cassettes in this series is not currently available at the Bentley Library. Contact the reference archivist to arrange for duplication of tapes.
Biographical / Historical
Peter Sparling is Professor of Dance at the University of Michigan School of Music. Well known as both performer and choreographer, he has danced with Martha Graham and Jose Limon.
Sparling got his first dance training while on a scholarship for violin performance at Interlochen Arts Academy. He added dance to his major and graduated in 1969, and then attended The Juilliard School, receiving his B.F.A. in 1973. While still at Juilliard, Sparling began touring with the Jose Limon Dance Company, traveling to Europe, Russia and Asia. He co-founded Dance Mobile with Janet Eilber, Ange Wolf and Diana Hart, all of whom he met at Interlochen. In 1974, he married another dancer he had met while at Interlochen, Shelley Washington. They divorced after three years.
In 1973, after the death of Jose Limon, Sparling was invited to join the Martha Graham Dance Company. Graham dramatically influenced Sparling's performance and his choreography, and he created and performed his own works during the six years he was with the Graham Company. When he left the company in 1979, he formed Peter Sparling Presents Solo Flight, and then the Peter Sparling Dance Company, as vehicles for his choreography. He continued to dance occasionally with the Graham Company until 1987.
In 1984, after several teaching residencies in such institutions as Barnard College in New York, Florida State University, Cloud Gate Dance Theatre in Taiwan and the Laban Centre for Movement Studies in London, Sparling was hired as Assistant Professor at the University of Michigan Dance Department. He was chair of the Department from 1988 through 1995. In 1984, he co-founded Ann Arbor Dance Works, the University of Michigan's resident dance company. In 1993, Peter founded the Peter Sparling Dance Co. a non-profit organization that continues today. Further information about Sparling's dance company or current work see http://www.dancegalleryfoundation.org.
Scope and Contents
The Peter Sparling Papers include materials relating to Sparling's dance training, performance, and teaching. The papers are divided into eight series: Background Materials, Choreography, Correspondence, Dance Companies, Programs, Reviews, Photographs, Performance, Audition, and Rehearsal Videos, and Posters.
Choreographers -- United States.; Dancers -- United States.; Ballet -- United States.; Ballet -- Study and teaching.; Choreography.; Ballet -- United States.; Dancers.; Posters.; Videotapes.; Motion pictures.; Photographs.; Sparling, Peter, 1951-; University of Michigan. -- Faculty.; University of Michigan. School of Music.; Sparling, Peter, 1951-; Sparling, Peter, Performances, 1951-
- Background Materials, 1967-1999
  Scope and Contents
  The Background Materials series, (.10 linear feet, 1967-1999), includes a curriculum vitae with a chronological list of Sparling's choreographic works through the year 1999, a journal written while he was on tour in the Soviet Union in 1973, news clippings, and other biographical materials.
  - Biographical Materials, 1988-1999; undated (Box 1)
  - Curriculum vitae
    - 2000 (Box 1)
      General
      includes list of choreographic works
    - 2009, .PDF file
  - Dance Slippers (one pair) (Box 1)
  - Drawings, 1967; circa 1994; undated (Box 1)
    includes photograph--see also oversize series Posters
  - Journals
    - "Dance History" (project for dance class at Juilliard School), 1972 (Box 1)
    - "Soviet Journal: An informal account of my life and impressions while on the U.S. State Department-sponsored tour of the Jose Limon Dance Company through the Soviet Union February 23-March 21, 1973 by Peter Sparling," 1973 (Box 1)
  - Music for Dance, 1988-1989; undated (Box 1)
  - "Personal Reflections: On Dancing, Making Dances, and 'Histories of Sexuality,'", circa 1990-1991 (Box 1)
- Choreography, 1982-1999
  In the Choreography series, (.20 linear feet, 1982-1999), are notes and sketches for several choreographic works by Sparling. The works represented--including "Delirium Waltz," "Seven Enigmas" and "Travelogue"--are all from the 1990s, except for "A Fearful Symmetry," which was first performed in 1981. The materials are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - "Acts of Light,", circa 1999 (Box 1)
  - "Dance for 'The Wave Field,'", 1995 (Box 1)
  - "Delirium Waltz,", 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - "A Fearful Symmetry,", 1982-1988; undated (Box 1)
  - Script of Lecture/Demonstration in San Jose, Costa Rica, undated (Box 1)
  - Seven Enigmas
    - Funding, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Proposals and Scripts, 1996-1997 (Box 1)
  - "Travelogue: A Pilgrimage for Dancers, Narrator and One-Man Band in Three Acts"
    - Notes and Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Scripts and Newsclippings, 1994-1995; undated (Box 1)
  - "Unfinished (to the Schubert Symphony),", 1997 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1979-1998
  The Correspondence series, (.10 linear feet, 1979-1998), primarily contains letters written by Sparling to his mother, and postcards sent to his family while he was on tour. The letters cover the years from his first at Interlochen in 1966 through 1999, and include personal insights and descriptions of people, performances, and life on tour.
  - undated (Box 1)
  - 1966-1998, 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Postcards kept by the Sparling family from P.S. on tour, 1974-1979 (Box 1)
    removed from scrapbook
- Dance Companies, 1974-1999
  The Dance Companies series, (.10 linear feet, 1974-1999), includes clippings and publicity from three dance companies Sparling was intimately involved with--Ann Arbor Dance Works, Dance Gallery/Peter Sparling & Co., and the Martha Graham Dance Company.
  - Ann Arbor Dance Works, undated (Box 1)
  - Dance Gallery/Peter Sparling & Co., 1997-1999 (Box 1)
  - Martha Graham Dance Company
    - Clippings, 1991; undated (Box 1)
    - Publicity, 1974-1988; undated (Box 1)
- Programs, 1961-2001
  The series, Programs (.25 linear feet, 1961-2001), contains an incomplete set of performance programs for events at which Sparling performed, or performances of his works by other dancers. The programs are dated 1961 through 2001, and include programs from Sparling's early performances with the violin. Most contain program notes, and biographical information about the performers.
  - undated (Box 1)
  - 1961-1968 (Box 1)
  - 1970-1979 (Box 1)
  - 1980-1984 (Box 1)
  - 1985-1989 (Box 1)
  - 1990-1997 (Box 1)
  - 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - 2000-2001 (Box 1)
- Reviews, 1966-1999
  The Reviews series, (.25 linear feet, 1966-1999), contains clippings of articles about works or performances by Sparling. These articles include critical reviews, biographical pieces, and general announcements.
  - undated (Box 1)
  - 1966-1999, 9 folders (Box 1)
- Photographs, 1972-1999
  The PHOTOGRAPHS series (one linear foot and one oversize box) includes prints, negatives, and slides. Photographs are divided into five categories: Sparling Choreography, Other Choreographers, Studio Shots, Non-Dance Photographs, and Oversize Photographs. The photographs are described by choreographer, title, type of photograph (performance, rehearsal, studio shot, head shot, or non-dance photograph), names of the performers (if applicable), location, date and photographer (if known). The numbers of prints, negatives and slides are also listed.
  - Sparling Choreography
    - "Aria degli Angeli della Terra", undated; 5 contact sheets (Box 2)
      Performance by Ann Arbor Dance Works: Sparling, James Moreno, Wendy Alga and Mary Fehrenbach
      Location: U-M McIntosh Theater
      Photographer: Christopher Montagna
    - "Aria degli Angeli della Terra", circa 1988; 24 negatives; 12 prints (Box 2)
      Performance by Sparling, Mary Fehrenbach, Wendy Alger and James Moreno
    - "As Quiet As...", 1972; 2 prints (Box 2)
      Performance by the dancers of National Music Camp
      Location: Kresge Auditorium, Interlochen, MI
      Photographer: Wayne Brill
    - "The Boy Who Played with Dolls", 1991; 1 contact sheets see also "Witness" for other contact sheet; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling solo
      Location: U-M Dance Building
      Photographer: Nat Ehrlich
    - "The Boy Who Played with Dolls", 1992; 1 contact sheets; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Studio shots; Sparling solo
      Location: NYC
      Photographer: Linda Alaniz
    - "The Boy Who Played with Dolls", February 27, 1992; 1 contact sheets (Box 2)
      Location: Theatre of the Riverside Church, NYC
      Photographer: Speliotis
    - "Bride of Grand Prairie, undated", 2 prints (Box 2)
      Performance by Performance Network: Sparling and Janet Lilly (and Tim Sparling)
      Location: Ann Arbor
    - "Bright Bowed River", 1985/86; 3 contact sheets; 3 prints (Box 2)
      shots; Sparling solo
      Photographer: Bob Kalmbach
    - "1989De Profundis", 3 contact sheets; 2 prints (Box 2)
      Photographer: Nat Ehrlich (Ann Arbor)
    - "Divining Rod", 1975; 1 negatives; 4 contact sheets; 13 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling solo in "Dance Uptown"
      Location: Minor Latham Playhouse, Barnard College, NYC
      Photographer: Lois Greenfield
    - "Divining Rod", June 1979; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Photographer: Amanda Kreglow
    - "Divining Rod", 1981; 1 contact sheets see also 4 oversize contact sheets; 13 prints (Box 2)
      Location: Stockholm
      Photographer: Lesley Leslie-Spinks
    - "Divining Rod", undated; 2 contact sheets; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Photographer: Johan Elbers
    - "Double Exposure", 1991; 2 negatives; 1 contact sheets; 4 prints (Box 2)
    - "A Fearful Symmetry", 1984; 2 prints (Box 2)
      Location: Victorian College of the Arts, Melbourne, Australia
      Photographer: Russell Naughton
    - "A Fearful Symmetry", 1987; 4 contact sheets; 9 prints (Box 2)
      Photographer: Robert Chase
    - "A Fearful Symmetry", 1987; 6 contact sheets (Box 2)
    - "A Fearful Symmetry", undated; 2 contact sheets (Box 2)
    - "Herald's Round", 1979; 1 contact sheets (Box 2)
      Performance in Choreographer's Showcase; Sparling, Bert Terborg and George White
      Location: Marymount Manhattan Theater, NYC
    - "L'Histoire du Soldat,", 1987; 1 prints (Box 2)
      shot; Sparling, Linda Spriggs and Bill DeYoung
      Photographer: Bob Chase
    - "In Stride", June 1979; 4 prints (Box 2)
    - "Jealousy", 1994; 1 contact sheets color; see also 1 oversize color print (Box 2)
      Photographer: David Smith
    - "Johnny Angel", 1993; 1 prints (Box 2)
      shots; Sparling and dancers
      Location: Power Center, Ann Arbor
    - "Johnny Angel", April, 1995; 6 prints color; 1 items (Box 2)
      Performance; Campania de Camara Danza Una
      Location: Universidad Nacional Cidea
      Photographer: unidentified
    - "Landscape with Bridge", March 1981; 1 prints; 4 prints color (Box 2)
      Performance; Ballet Gulbenkian
      Location: Lisbon
    - "The Lantern-Night Excursion of Chung Q'ui", June 1979; 1 prints (Box 2)
    - "The Lantern-Night Excursion of Chung Q'ui", 1979; 2 contact sheets see other contact sheets with "Suite to Sleep"; 1 prints color (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling, Kevin Keenan, George White and Bert Terborg
    - "Man Dancing, Dancing Man", 1986; 3 prints; 1 prints color (Box 2)
      Performance in "Up Over, Down Under;" Sparling solo
    - "Miranda on the Veranda", 1991; 1 prints for contact sheet, see "The Boy Who Played with Dolls" (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling and Susan Caligaris
    - "Miranda on the Veranda", 1991; 19 photographs color (Box 2)
      Photographer: David Caligaris
    - "Nocturnes", 1985; 5 prints (Box 2)
    - "Nocturnes for Eurydice" February [1978], 5 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Peggy Lyman
      Location: [Cincinnati?]
      Photographer: Sandy Underwood
    - "Nocturnes for Eurydice", May 1978; 4 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Janet Eilber
    - "Nocturnes for Eurydice", 1978/79; 2 contact sheets; 1 prints (Box 2)
    - "Ode", 1988; 1 prints (Box 2)
      composition; Sparling solo
    - "Once in a Blue Moon", 1977; 2 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling and Susan McGuire
      Photographer: Tom Rawe
    - "Once in a Blue Moon", 1978; 2 contact sheets; 2 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling, Janet Eilber and Jeffrey Urban
    - "Once in a Blue Moon", 1978; 5 prints (Box 2)
      Location: Theatre of the Riverside Church
      Photographer: Amanda Kreglow, NYC
    - "Reel", 1983; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling and Madcat Ruth
    - "Rondo", 1987; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Rehearsal; Sparling, Tom Cocco and Jim Moreno
    - "Rounding the Square", 1989; 1 prints see also 1 oversize print (Box 2)
      Performance; Caroline Sutton
      Location: unidentified
      Photographer: Deborah Weisbach
    - "Rounding the Square", June 1989; 3 contact sheets; 3 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling, Melissa Trombley, Caroline Sutton and James Moreno
    - "Rounding the Square", 1989; 2 contact sheets; 5 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling and Ann Arbor Dance Works dancers
    - "Rounding the Square", 1989/90; 36 negatives; 1 prints color; 4 prints black and white; 6 slides color (Box 2)
      shots; Sparling, Caroline Sutton, Melissa Trombley and Arlene Leitch
    - "Sancerre", 1988; 1 prints (Box 2)
      shot; Sparling solo
      Location: [Ann Arbor?]
    - "Sancerre", 1988; 3 contact sheets; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling and Performance Network dancer
    - "Sitting Harlequin", 1972; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Location: Interlochen, MI
    - "Sitting Harlequin", 1979; 6 contact sheets; 14 prints (Box 2)
      shot for Dance Theater Workshop; Sparling solo
    - "Six Bagatelles", 1972; 5 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling, Janet Eilber, Ange Wolf and Diana Hart
    - "Suite to Sleep", 1978; 2 contact sheets; 6 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Christine Dakin, Bert Terborg, Lana Carroll, Elisa King, Sophie Giovanola, Helen Jones, Jill Marvin and Susan Miller
    - "Suite to Sleep", 1979; 1 contact sheets (Box 2)
      Performance; Christine Dakin and Bert Terborg
    - "Swing Serenade", 1982; 3 negatives; 8 prints (Box 2)
      Performance for Ballet Gulbenkian
    - "Tableaux", 1985; 1 prints (Box 2)
      shot; Sparling and Bill DeYoung
    - "The Tempest", undated; 4 contact sheets; 3 prints (Box 2)
    - Rehearsal; Sparling, Jane Hedal, Joyce Herring, Anthony Morgan and Barry Smith (Box 2)
      Location: Hirabayashi Dance Studio, NYC
    - "This Place", 1979; 2 contact sheets (Box 2)
      Performance for Choreographer's Showcase; Sparling, Thea Barnes, Kevin Keenan, Charles Brown and Dindi Lidge
    - "Three Farewells", 1979; 2 contact sheets see also "Sitting Harlequin"; 13 prints (Box 2)
      shots for Dance Theater Workshop; Sparling solo
    - "Unfinished", 1997; 3 contact sheets (Box 2)
      Performance by University Dance Company
      Photographer: Glenn Bering
    - "What She Forgot He Remembered", circa 1980; 3 contact sheets (Box 2)
      Rehearsal; Sparling and Jane [?]
      Location: Kacuko Hirakyashi Dance Studio, Manhattan
    - "What She Forgot He Remembered", 1980; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling and Jane [?]
    - "Wings," by Peter Sparling, 1989; 8 prints (Box 2)
      Location: [Ann Arbor]
    - "Wintertanze II", 1989; 2 contact sheets; 1 prints (Box 2)
    - "Wintertanze II", 1989; 29 negatives; 6 prints; 4 slides color (Box 2)
      Location: [NYC?]
      Photographer: [Linda Alaniz?]
    - "Witness", 1991; 1 contact sheets; 1 prints (Box 2)
    - "Zig-Zag", July 8, 1990; 1 contact sheets; 2 prints; 2 prints color (Box 2)
      Performance; Sparling, Tom Cocco, Mary Fehrenbach, Betsy Glenn and David Genson
      Photographer: Stephen Graham
  - Other Choreographers
    - Various
      - Choreographer's Showcase, February 1979; 5 contact sheets (Box 2)
        Performance; Sparling and the Martha Graham School
    - Various
      - Lincoln Center Student Program, [pre-1975] (Box 2)
        Performance; Sparling, Joel Sachs, Barbara Hendricks, Rylann Jordan, Janet Sonres, Janet Eilber, Dorian Williams, and Ange Wolf
        Location: Alice Tully Hall, NYC
    - Bostian, Jean Parsons
      - Unidentified, circa 1968; 3 prints (Box 2)
        Performance; Sparling and dancers
        Location: Eastern Michigan University Summer Dance Workshop, Ypsilanti, MI
    - Corning, Beth
      - "Journey" 7 prints (see also 1 oversize print), 1982 (Box 2)
        Performance; Sparling and Beth Corning
    - Earl, David
      - "Atlantis", 1978; 3 negatives; 15 prints (Box 2)
        Location: Toronto
        Photographer: Frank Richards
    - Graham, Martha
      - "Diversion of Angels", 1975; 1 prints (Box 2)
        Performance; Sparling, Tim Wengerd, Lucinda Mitchell, David Hatch Walker, Eric Newton, Bonnie Oda Momsay and Shelley Washington
        Location: [NYC]
        Photographer: Martha Swope
      - "Diversion of Angels", 1976; 2 prints (Box 2)
        Performance; Sparling and Janet Eilber
      - "Diversion of Angels", 1999; 1 prints color (Box 2)
        Rehearsal; Sparling and Lisa Catrett-Belrose
      - "Night Journey", 1978/79; 1 prints (Box 2)
      - "Plain of Prayer", 1975/76; 1 prints (Box 2)
        Performance; Sparling, Lucinda Mitchell, Diana Hurt and Jessica Chao
      - "Plain of Prayer", 1977; 2 prints (Box 2)
        shots; Sparling and Janet Eilber
      - "Seraphic Dialogue", 1977; 1 prints (Box 2)
    - Hug, William
      - "Lines and Designs", 1972; 3 prints (Box 2)
        Performance by Dance Mobile: Sparling, Janet Eilber, Ange Wolf and Diana Hart
    - Limon, Jose
      - "Chaconne" 4 contact sheets and 6 prints, 1985/86 (Box 2)
      - "Chaconne", 1986; 1 prints (Box 2)
      - "Chaconne", 1988; 3 prints (Box 2)
    - Widaryanto
      - Javanese Dance/Drama, 1998; 1 prints see also 1 oversize print (Box 2)
        Performance; Sparling and Charley Sullivan
        Location: Hill Auditorium
  - Studio Shots (not for specific choreography)
    - 1977
      - Sparling (Head shots), 1 negatives; 3 prints (Box 2)
    - September 1978
      - Sparling, 5 contact sheets; 3 prints (Box 2)
    - 1978
      - Sparling (Head shots), 3 prints (Box 2)
    - 1978
      - Sparling, 3 prints (Box 2)
    - 1979
      - Sparling, 1 prints (Box 2)
    - 1979
      - Sparling (Studio shots/Head shots), 2 negatives; 5 contact sheets; 5 prints (Box 2)
        Location: London
        Photographer: Richard Massey
    - 1979
      - Sparling, 4 contact sheets; 4 prints (Box 2)
    - 1979
      - Sparling, 8 contact sheets; 4 prints (Box 2)
    - 1980
      - Sparling (Head shots), 28 negatives; 1 contact sheets; 4 prints (Box 2)
    - 1981
      - Sparling, 1 negatives; 2 prints (Box 2)
        Photographer: Dave Fullard
    - 1983
      - Sparling, 1 prints (Box 2)
    - 1985
      - Sparling and Bill DeYoung (for Ann Arbor Dance Works), 1 prints (Box 2)
    - 1986
      - Sparling, Peter Matthews and Tim Sparling (for "Up Over, Down Under"), 1 contact sheets; 3 prints (Box 2)
    - 1994
      - Sparling and Terri Sarris, 2 contact sheets (Box 2)
    - 1998
      - Sparling (Head shot), 2 negatives; 1 prints (Box 2)
        Photographer: John Schultz
    - Undated
      - Sparling (Head shots), 7 prints (Box 2)
        Photographer: Christopher H. Montagna
  - Non-Dance Photographs
    - Orchestra photographs, 1965; 1967; 2 prints (Box 2)
      Location: Plymouth and Interlochen, MI
    - Dance Mobile: Sparling, Diana Hart, Ange Wolf and Janet Eilber., 1972; 2 prints (Box 2)
    - National Music Camp: Sparling, Janet Eilber, Ange Wolf, Michael Pilafian and students, 1972; 1 prints (Box 2)
    - Snapshot with the Queen Mother, July 1979; 1 prints (Box 2)
      Location: Covent Garden, London
      Photographer: Donald Southern
    - Studio shots for videotaping of Beth Corning's "Journey;" Sparling, Beth Corning and anonymous clown, 1982; 3 prints (Box 2)
      Location: Circus House, Stockholm
    - Ann Arbor Dance Works group photograph; Sparling, Jessica Fogel, Gay Delanghe, Bill DeYoung and Linda Spriggs, 1986/87; 1 prints cut up (Box 2)
    - After performance; Sparling and video technician Alec Friedman, 1987; 1 prints color (Box 2)
    - Faculty Recognition Award; Sparling and James Duderstadt, 1992; 2 prints (Box 2)
      Location: University of Michigan
    - Cast of "The Tempest," U-M School of Music, 1999; 1 prints; 2 prints color (Box 2)
      Location: U-M Mendelsohn Theater
    - Sparling applying makeup for Jose Limon's "The Winged", undated; 1 photographs color (Box 2)
      Location: Juilliard
    - Sparling with Julia Goodman and Elizabeth Bergmann, Undated; 3 photographs color (Box 2)
      Location: Betty Pease Studio Theater, U-M Dance Building
    - Reception for American Choreographer's Festival, University Musical Society; Sparling, Bebe Miller and company, Robert Small and Leslie Friedman, Undated; 32 photographs color (Box 2)
    - Sculpture of Sparling by Norma Penchansky-Glaser, Undated; 1 prints (Box 2)
    - Personal, candids (at a wedding reception), circa 1985; 2 photographs color (Box 2)
  - Oversize Photographs
    - "Aria degli Angeli della Terra," by Sparling, 1988; 5 contact sheets (Box 5)
      also includes works by Bill DeYoung, Jessica Fogel, Gay Delanghe and Linda Spriggs
      Performance; Sparling, Mary Fehrenbach, Wendy Alger and James Moreno
    - "Chaconne," by Jose Limon, 1986; 1 prints color (Box 5)
      Location: U-M McIntosh Hall
    - "Divining Rod," by Sparling, 1981; 4 contact sheets (Box 5)
      Location: [Stockholm?]
    - "Jealousy," by Sparling, 1994; 1 prints color (Box 5)
      Performance (composite); Sparling and Janet Lilly
    - "Journey," by Beth Corning, 1982; 1 prints (Box 5)
      Performance; Sparling and Corning
    - "Nocturnes," by Sparling 1986 (Box 5)
      Performance; Sparling, Linda Spriggs and Marsha Pabalis
    - "Rounding the Square," by Sparling, 1989; 1 prints (Box 5)
      Performance; Sparling, James Moreno and Caroline Sutton
    - Widaryanto: Javanese Dance/Drama, 1998; 1 prints (Box 5)
      Location: U-M Hill Auditorium
- Performance, Audition, and Rehearsal Videos
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted Access: All performances in DVC-Pro format are preservation copies dubbed from original VHS and 3/4-inch tape. Arrangements for duplication need to be made with the Reference Archivist. Equipment needed to view digital video cassettes is not available at the Bentley Library. Access to some of the online digital files is restricted to the viewing in the Bentley Library reading room and the School of Music.